dofus.jp 2019-11-22

# Privacy Policy - Ankama - DOFUS, the strategic MMORPG - DOFUS, the strategic MMORPG

## Article no. 1 : Preamble

This Privacy Policy Statement informs you of the terms and procedures for the collection, processing and use of your personal data by the company Ankama Games, registered with the Lille Metropolitan Area Companies and Commerce Register (RCS) under number 492 360 730, (hereinafter the “ **Company** ”, “ **Ankama** ” or “ **We** ”/“ **Us** ”). This statement also informs you of your data protection rights and obligations when using Ankama websites (the “ **Websites** ”), video games (the “ **Games** ”) and applications (the “ **Applications** ”) published by the Company for computers or mobile devices and that provide a link to this Privacy Policy.

The Websites, Games and Applications are collectively referred to as the " **Services** ".

Ankama Games is responsible for collecting personal data, which is accessible to all the companies in the Ankama group.

By accessing or using the Services, you acknowledge having read this Privacy Policy and consent to it.

_Information for Minors_ : We keep the information you provide us (first and last name, date of birth, email address, mailing address, telephone number) to be able to communicate with you regarding your account, monitor your purchases, help you resolve security problems that may affect your account, and send you information about our Services. When creating your account, We ask you to enter an account name and a password: This account name and this password will allow you to access our Services, notably our Games. Warning: This account name and password must remain secret; **never communicate them to other people**. 

You have the right to access and rectify your data. To exercise this right and obtain the communication or deletion of information concerning you, write to us with the help of your parents, either through our website [https://support.ankama.com/hc/en-us](https://support.ankama.com/hc/fr), or via postal mail at ANKAMA – Infos Personnelles, 75 bd d'Armentières, BP 60403, 59057 Roubaix cedex 1, France.

## Article no. 2 : Data Collected

**2.1 _The information you provide us_**

When you use our Services, personal data may be requested.

The expression "personal data" denotes any and all information directly or indirectly identifying you, by reference to an identification number or to one or more elements specific to you.

We will not ask you for this information if you are only visiting our Websites, but you will not be able to access certain areas of those Websites (such as the forums) unless you register.

When personal data are collected, you will be informed whether the information We are asking you to disclose is required or optional, and the possible consequences of not providing the data.

**2.1.1 When you create an Ankama account** (" **Ankama Account** "), We ask you to provide the following information: account name, password, and email address.

**2.1.2 When you make purchases on our Websites,** we ask you to provide payment information. The specific information requested depends on the payment method you select. When you make your first purchase on our Websites, you must certify your Ankama Account by providing us with the following information: title, full name, date of birth, mailing address, country of residence, and secret question/answer. We record your purchase history on our Websites: date, amount, article(s) bought, means of payment used.

**2.1.3 In the "Account Management" section of our Websites,** you can consult the information related to your Ankama Account, fill in information about you, and modify some of this information. The information that you can provide in the Account Management section is: title, full name, date of birth, mailing address, country of residence, and secret question/answer. If you provide all this information in the Account Management section, your Ankama Account will be certified. If you have already certified your Ankama Account, you will be able to modify some of this information.

The Account Management section also lets you add your mobile phone number, one or more secondary mailing address(es), your preferences about receiving newsletters by email and commercial offers by text message, the language you prefer we use to communicate with you, the parameters of your Ankabox messaging service, and a personalized description of your profile (visible to all Website users).

**2.1.4 When you contact our customer service department ("Support"),** you must create a ticket via an online form. Depending on the subject of your request, information may be requested, notably your full name and email address. In some cases, We will ask that you prove your identity by providing an official proof of identity.

If it is your first time contacting Support, an email will be sent to you to inform you that you will need to create a helpdesk account so that your request may be processed. To do so, all you need to do is click on the link provided in the email. You will then be asked to provide a password, but this is not a prerequisite to the creation of a helpdesk account or the processing of your request. However, you must do so if you wish to consult the response provided.

**2.1.5 When you participate in a contest, tournament, lottery or survey,** We may request personal data such as your full name, age, mailing address, and email address.

**2.2 _Information We collect automatically when you use Services_**

When you use the Services, We collect information on the Services you use and how you use them:

**2.2.1 When you surf our Websites,** We collect the following information: IP address, connection date and time, interventions on Websites and discussion forums, interactions with the Websites (pages visited, etc.), and preferences (languages). We use cookies or other similar technologies to collect some of this data. Please see Article 5 for more information on cookies.

**2.2.2 When you install and use our Games,** We collect the following information: game data (data exchange log and history, connection log and history, and generally speaking all data connected to actions performed in the Games), data on your hardware and software configuration (when installing a game and in the event of a modification to your computer's hardware), and IP address.

**2.2.3 When you install and use our Applications,** We collect the following information: IP address, connection date and time, and information on your mobile device (brand, model, operating system version, the device's unique identifier).

**2.3 _When you decide to log in to our Services using a social media account or game platform_**

The Company may offer you the possibility of logging in to certain Services using a social media or game platform identifier. This connection method will sometimes be required to access certain features of the Services, particularly to offer you the possibility of interacting with other users of these networks and platforms.

When logging in using social media or a game platform, you will be asked to agree that certain information about you be shared with Ankama. By agreeing to this information being shared, Ankama shall have access to this data and will retain some of it.

Thus, by connecting to some of our Applications via the social network Facebook, Ankama will have access to your friends list, but will not retain it. This access allows us to let you use some of the social network's features that involve other users. We keep your Facebook identifier so we can recognize you on several mobile devices and to re-attribute your progress acquired during your prior logins.

When you authorize our Services to interact with social media or game platforms, we may share data concerning you with your contacts. This data includes your name, profile photo on the social media concerned, and your progress and/or ranking in our games.

These social media and game platforms are created and managed by third parties, and are not controlled by Us. We invite you to refer to their terms of use and their privacy policies to understand how these third parties process your data and what data they may communicate to us.

## Article no. 3 : Purpose and Legal Basis

Your personal data may be processed for different reasons and based on different legal bases:

**3.1 We use your data because they are necessary for the proper execution of a contract between you and Us.** Thus, your data will be processed to:

  * create, manage, and monitor Ankama accounts;
  * allow you to access and use the Services;
  * allow you to purchase products and services from our Websites, and to allow you to handle, manage, and track your orders;
  * allow you to communicate with other Service users, notably in our chat rooms, discussion forums, and via the Ankabox;
  * send you important information about the Services and any other information in relation to your Ankama Account and the actions performed with it (for example: order confirmation emails, forgotten password emails/text messages, emails allowing you to activate Ankama Shield protection);
  * manage claims and after-sales service; and
  * assist you in the event of technical issues using our Services.

**3.2 We use data based on our legitimate interests when such use does not infringe on your rights and freedoms.** Thus, your data will be processed to:

  * improve our Services, notably to improve Game performance and experience, or manage bugs;
  * ensure the safety of your Ankama Account; offer you commercial events such as contests, lotteries and/or tournaments;
  * prevent and detect unusual behavior, and notably fight against payment fraud;
  * monitor and track in-Game behavior and compliance with the rules set forth in our Terms of Use, Terms and Conditions of Sale, and all other documents that you agree to when using our Services;
  * personalize and improve the advertising We display through websites and third-party services; and
  * measure the performance of our marketing campaigns.

As part of efforts to combat payment fraud and in-game cheating, automatic decisions may be made based on your interactions with the Services and the data you provide.  We may notably limit or suspend your access to our Services (notably through sanctions applied to your Ankama Account) if this automatic processing detects a user or activity that presents, in our opinion, a risk of fraud or cheating.

**3.3 We request your consent** to send you commercial offers and newsletters via email and/or text message. 

Please note that you may withdraw your consent at any time, without infringing on the legality of the processing done based on the consent granted prior to its withdrawal. To do so, you must go to your Account Management section to set your preferences regarding receiving commercial offers and newsletters. Our emails and text messages also contain a link or keyword to send to unsubscribe.

**3.4 We process some of your data when it is necessary to comply with our legal obligations** (notably to comply with our accounting and fiscal obligations or when the law requires us to retain specific data).

## Article no. 4 : Disclosure of Personal Data

Ankama may have recourse to third-party service providers who collect your personal data in Ankama's name and on behalf of Ankama, or with whom Ankama will share your data, in a secure manner, notably with the aim of ensuring the completion of the tasks necessary to execute your order, deliver products, process your payments, ensure management of customer relations, provide a chat messaging service, fight payment fraud, provide advertising services, send you text messages (notably to recover your login information), or even propose surveys.

These providers may be located outside the European Union, in particular in the Asia-Pacific region, and in North and South America. Ankama has taken every necessary precaution to ensure that your personal data are sufficiently protected, either under contractual data protection clauses established by the European Commission or by ensuring that these data transfers happen with American companies that adhere to Privacy Shield principles.

Ankama may also communicate your personal data to the appropriate authorities, at their request, in the framework of legal proceedings, legal inquiries, and information requests by the authorities, or to comply with other legal requirements.  

## Article no. 5 : Cookies

When a person visits our Websites, cookies or similar files may be installed, particularly on the web user's computer hard disk.

**5.1 _What is a cookie?_**

A cookie is a small file installed on your hard drive by the server of the website you visit.

It contains several pieces of information:

  * the name of the server that wrote it;
  * a unique identifying number;
  * it may also include an expiry date.

This information is sometimes stored on your computer in a plain text file that can be accessed by a server in order to read and record information.

There are different types of cookies:

  * session cookies, which are deleted when the session closes;
  * permanent cookies, which are stored;
  * flash cookies.

You will find more information about cookies on the CNIL website (<http://www.cnil.fr/vos-droits/vos-traces/les-cookies/>) and on the website <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/>.

**5.2 _The cookies installed by our Websites_**

The cookies We use on our Websites fall into the following categories:

**5.2.1 Cookies that are strictly necessary:** These cookies are essential to the operation of our Websites and to provide you with the services requested. These cookies are designed to identify you, help make our Services secure, and allow you to access your Ankama Account and manage your orders.

**5.2.2 Feature cookies:** These cookies aim to enhance your browsing experience on our Websites. We use them to store your choices and preferences (such as the language you use), to store previously entered information so you do not have to enter it again when you next visit, and to remind Us of already-visited pages so as not to display them again.

**5.2.3 Cookies for advertising and to track traffic:** These cookies allow us to measure the effectiveness of advertising campaigns on our Websites (number of views, number of clicks, etc.) and help Us tailor advertisements promoting our Services displayed on third-party websites (targeted advertising). Additionally, for statistical purposes, We use an analysis and utilization tool for events occurring after e-mails are sent, such as messages being opened, clicks, and the termination of subscriptions or registrations. This tool operates using cookies.

For this purpose, the Company uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. (" **Google** "). Google Analytics uses cookies, which are text files stored on your computer that make it possible to analyze your use of the website. The data generated by these cookies concerning your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers located in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, for compiling reports on website activity, and for providing other services relating to website activity and Internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law or where these third parties process data on behalf of Google, including and in particular, the website operator. Google will not match your IP address with any other data held by Google. By using this website, you expressly consent to the processing of personal data by Google in the manner and for the purposes described above. For further information on how Google uses your data when your visit our Websites, visit: [http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/partners/](http://www.google.com/intl/fr/policies/privacy/partners/).

We also use Google Analytics to collect certain anonymous demographic data (age, gender) concerning Website visitors, as well as information concerning their interests. For this purpose, jointly with third-party suppliers including Google, We use proprietary cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie). Ankama uses this data to gain a clearer understanding of its Website users' profiles. This information does not allow us to identify you. Furthermore, this demographic data shall in no circumstances be associated with any personal data you may have communicated to Ankama.

**5.2.4 Cookies aiming to improve Website interactivity and improve user experience:** Our Websites rely on certain services offered by third-party websites. These are notably:

  * chat services (iAdvize)
  * share buttons (Facebook, Twitter and Google Plus)
  * social media flows (Twitter, Facebook, and YouTube)
  * information on communication tools (Discord)
  * videos shown on our Websites (YouTube, Twitch)
  * geo-tracking services (Google Maps)
  * GIF services (Giphy)

**5.2.5 Flash cookies:** In some situations, We may use shared local objects (commonly called "Flash cookies") to memorize certain information, such as your progress in browser-based games offered by the Company.  Flash cookies differ from browser cookies by the amount and type of data stored, as well as by their storage method. Cookie management tools available through your browser will not delete Flash cookies. You can access your Flash management tools directly from the Adobe website: [http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/fr/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html). Please note that by deactivating Flash cookies, you will no longer have access to certain features that facilitate your experience on our Websites.

**5.3 _Cookies We place on websites that carry our advertising_**

Third-party sites may carry advertising banners promoting the activities of Ankama entities. In these circumstances, when a web user clicks on such a banner, a cookie is installed on their terminal. These cookies are used for the following purposes:

  * to record the number of times our advertising content broadcast on third-party sites is viewed and clicked on, to identify such content and websites, and to determine the number of users clicking on each content item;
  * to calculate the amounts due to the entitled parties in the advertising dissemination chain (third-party site publishers and advertising networks) and to generate statistics; and
  * to track subsequent browsing from your terminal on our Websites.

**5.4 _Cookie management_**

When you visit our Websites for the first time, a banner informs you of the presence of cookies to track visits and advertising, and of cookies destined to improve Website interactivity and enhance user experience; and we invite you to indicate your preferences. You can set your cookie preferences to accept or refuse cookies at any time by visiting the "Cookie Management" page present at the bottom of every page on our Websites. You may set your preferences either overall for the Websites, or service by service. 

## Article no. 6 : Discussion Spaces and User Profiles

The Services may contain discussion spaces, particularly in the form of forums or chat rooms. You may also personalize your user profile. Ankama reminds you that any and all personal information divulged in forums, chat rooms and profiles becomes public information and can be reused by anyone. Users must therefore be very cautious when considering communicating personal information on this type of service.

In any event, Ankama strongly advises that you do not publish sensitive personal information, particularly information concerning your racial or ethnic origins, your political opinions, your philosophical or religious beliefs, your membership in a trade union, your genetic and biometric information, and any information concerning your health or sexual life.

If you choose to publish such information on our Services, you consent to it being visible to other members, as well as to any person accessing the Services.

Consequently, you should not provide any information that you do not wish to be made public.

## Article no. 7 : Security

The Company takes every appropriate technical and organizational measure, given the nature of the data and the risks inherent in data processing, to preserve a high level of data security, and in particular, to prevent it from becoming distorted or damaged, or from being accessed by unauthorized third parties.

Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology is therefore used to encrypt certain data; physical and logical backup procedures are implemented; and the HTTPS encryption protocol is used to secure access to data.

The Company reserves the right to initiate proceedings against any person who attempts to gain access to personal information not concerning him/her.

## Article no. 8 : Third-party websites

Hypertext links on the Services may redirect you to third-party sites not belonging to Ankama.

We wish to draw your attention to the fact that the personal data protection polices of these various sites may differ from this Privacy Policy. We advise you, in all cases, to acquaint yourself with the personal data protection policies of each of those sites.

In any case, Ankama cannot be held responsible in the event that the content of such a site or sites breaches the statutory and regulatory provisions in force, or the terms of this Privacy Policy.

## Article no. 9 : Your Rights

Except where stipulated otherwise, You may exercise your rights set forth in this article:

  * either via the online Support at [https://support.ankama.com/hc/en-us](http://support.ankama.com/),
  * or by writing to:

ANKAMA – Infos Personnelles,  
75 bd d'Armentières, BP 60403,  
59057 Roubaix cedex 1, France.

Out of concern for your privacy and to protection your personal data, We must ascertain your identity before replying to your request. Accordingly, any request to exercise your rights must be accompanied by a copy of a signed identity document.

Your request will be processed as soon as possible, in accordance with the legal provisions in force.

**9.1 _Access right and portability right_ :** You have the right to obtain confirmation that your personal data are or are not processed by Ankama and, when they are, to access the said data and information pertaining to their processing. You may also, when this is technically feasible, exercise your right to portability.

**9.2 _Rectification right_ :** You have the right to obtain the rectification of your personal data that may be inexact or incomplete (and that you cannot rectify yourself in your Account Management section or via the mobile services made available by Ankama).

**9.3 _Erasure right_ :** We store your personal data as long as it is needed for the purposes set forth in the present policy. If you no longer want Us to process your data, you may ask Us to erase them and close your Ankama Account. Please note, however, that even if you exercise this right, We may retain some data for the following purposes:

  * We may retain some of your data to protect our legitimate interests, such as detecting and preventing fraud.
  * We may retain and use your data to comply with our legal obligations.
  * If you have posted comments on our Websites or if you have posted in our discussion forums, your comments and posts will still appear, but will not be attributed to you.

**9.4 _Right to restrict processing_ :** You have the right to restrict processing of your data in limited circumstances: (i) when you contest the accuracy of your data; (ii) when processing is illicit and you request the restriction of their use instead of their erasure; (iii) when We no longer need your data for processing but when you still need them to establish, exercise or defend rights in court; (iv) when you are opposed to processing by virtue of Article 9.5, during the verification of whether Ankama's legitimate motives prevail over yours.

**9.5 _Right to object_ :** You may object, at any time and for reasons linked to your individual situation, to the processing of your data when this processing is based on a legitimate interest. If you exercise this right, We will no longer process your data, unless We can show that there are legitimate and imperative reasons for the processing that prevail over your interests, rights and freedoms, or for the establishment, exercise or defense of rights in court.

You may object at any time to the processing of your data for direct marketing purposes. You may set your preferences regarding receiving commercial offers and newsletters by email and/or text message in your Account Management section. Our emails and text messages also contain a link or keyword to send to unsubscribe.

## Article no. 10 : Data Storage

We store your personal data as long as it is needed for the purposes set forth in the present policy, in compliance with laws and legislation in force. To know your rights to erasure, please see the article on "Your Rights".   

## Article no. 11 : Update

We reserve the right to amend this Privacy Policy at any time. Consequently, We advise you to refer to our "Privacy Policy" regularly.

Last amended: May 2018  

## Article no. 12 : Inquiries and Complaints

For any inquiry or complaint relating to our Privacy Policy, you may contact Us in French or in English:

  * by postal mail at the following address: ANKAMA – Infos Personnelles, 75 bd d'Armentières, BP 60403, 59057 Roubaix cedex 1, France; or
  * by email at: [privacy@ankama.com](mailto:privacy@ankama.com)

You may also contact our data protection delegate at the same addresses.

If, however, you believe that We have not met your expectations, you may submit a claim with a competent data protection supervisory authority.
